[SOUND] So
那么
filtering allows us to remove extraneous.
筛选让我们移除无关的数据
Zooming is a kind of filter where remove extraneous data based on
缩放也是一种根据数据坐标
the plotted coordinates of the data.
移除无关数据的筛选机制
When we select a zoom window,
当我们选择一个缩放窗口时
we chose to focus on some of the data based on its displayed coordinates and
我们根据数据的显示坐标来选择重点关注一些数据
to eliminate data outside of a window based on its displayed coordinates.
并且将窗口外的数据排除
That's a kind of filter based on displayed coordinates, but a filter can be applied
这是根据显示坐标的一类筛选机制 但除显示坐标外 筛选也可以应用
to other attributes of the data besides the displayed coordinates.
于数据的其他属性
And so in this case, we've got our plot of all the countries
在这个例子中 图中显示的是所有国家的
of based on population and life expectancy.
人口和预期寿命
We can filter out all the countries that are in other continents and
我们可以筛去其他大陆的国家而
focus just on the countries that are in say, Africa.
只关注某些国家 比如非洲的国家
And so by filtering on Africa, we only plot the countries in Africa and
所以按非洲筛选 我们只在图上显示非洲的国家
the data is spread out nicely and there's much less data here.
这样数据点分布得很好 这儿的数据点也少了很多
So we've got room to be able to plot the names of the individual countries and
所以我们有地方来加上各个国家的名称 然后
you can start to see the subset of the larger dataset that corresponds to Africa.
你可以看到大数据组中属于非洲的子集
And you realize that many of the countries that have low life
然后你会发现很多低预期寿命的国家
expectancy are in Africa, but also there's a separate
都在非洲 但同时也有另一
band of countries in Africa that have higher life expectancies.
部分国家有较高的预期寿命
And by plotting the names, you've now got room to see more of the details,
而将名字加在图上可以使你看到更多的细节
because of this filter.
因为采用了这个筛选机制
You can see that those countries are the ones located in Northern Africa and
你可以看到这些国家集中在北非
there's different ways of selecting data by applying filters.
通过运用各种筛选机制 可以有不同的选择数据的方法
If you have ordinal or nominal data, for example, continent.
如果你有定序型或定类型数据 比如大陆
Then you can click a check box, you can show all of the different categories and
那么你可以点击复选框 这样在显示的所有不同类别中
select the ones that you want to look at and the ones that you don't want to
你可以选择想要查看和不想要
be plotted or if you want to look at quantitative data.
在图上出现的数据 或者如果你想要看的是定量的数据
For example, if we want to look at countries based on gross domestic product
比如 如果我们想要根据国民生产总值
or other quantitative fields, then we can set a range with a minimum and
或其他定量的条件筛选国家 我们可以设定一个最小
a maximum value and filter out data above or below these extremal
最大值的范围来筛去超过或低于临界值
values in order to focus on certain subsets of a quantitative range.
的数据 从而只关注某个定量的子集
So in tableau, it's quite easy to filter data based on attributes,
所以在tableau里 根据属性筛选数据是很容易的
you would just drag the attribute into this filter box.
你就将属性拽到这个Filter框里
And so in this case, if we have our countries displayed here
所以在这个例子中 如果我们显示在这儿的国家
differentiated by putting the country in the marks box,
是将国家放进这个marks框里来区分的
we may want to filter the countries based on continent.
我们或许想要根据大陆来筛选国家
And so, I dragged the Region dimension into the filter box and
那么我将 Region 变量拽到 filter 框里
that will filter based on regions.
这样就可以根据区域筛选数据了
And so now since region, these continents are basically a category,
所以区域 也就是这些大陆 事实上是一种分类
they're presented to me in check boxes.
它们以复选框的形式呈现
And so if I want to only look at a subset of the country say,
所以如果我想查看某一部分的国家 比如
Africa, I can just click Africa and then click OK.
非洲 我就点击 Africa 然后点击 OK
And now I'm only looking at the countries associated with Africa, the countries
那么现在我所看到的是跟非洲相关的国家 在非洲
on the continent of Africa and you can see there's a big differentiation here
大陆上的国家 你可以看到在上面的这些国家
between these countries Entries t the top and the countries at the bottom.
和下面的这些国家之间有很大的区别
And in fact, we can zoom in a little bit further to give us more
事实上 我们可以再放大一点 这样更高的屏幕分辨率
screen resolution to take a look at them.
可以让我们看得更清楚一些
And then if we want to know what those countries are, then I can drag country
如果我想知道这些是哪些国家 我可以把 country 键
into the label box here and we can get labels for each one of these countries.
放到label框里 然后我们每个国家都有一个标签
And you can see that the countries in Northern Africa tend to have
你可以看到位于北非的国家比
a higher life expectancy than the countries in the rest of Africa.
非洲其他国家的预期寿命要高
We don't want to overwhelm a display of a lot of information with further details,
我们不想要过度的显示很多细节的信息
especially when those details are extraneous and
特别是无关的细节会
distract us from general trends that we should be seeing in the data and
将我们的注意力从我们应该看到数据的大趋势上分散开
a very common way of doing this is with a tool tip.
一个非常普遍的解决方法是用提示工具
If your mouse is sitting over a data item, then a little pop-up
如果你将鼠标放在一个数据项上 就会有一个小弹窗
window will come up and give you the detail based on that data.
弹出并显示这个数据项的细节
And maybe some items that, like you can select only that item or
或者其它的一些功能 比如你可以只选择那个数据或者
you can exclude that item and look at other operations based on that item.
你可以排除那个数据或者查看该数据的其它一些操作
A second way of finding details on demand is a field selection.
第二种按需看细节的方法是变量选择
You can select a field of your dataset and
你可以选择数据组的一个变量然后
you can find the data points that field corresponds to or
找到这个变量关联的数据点 或者
a certain setting of that field corresponds to that get highlighted.
这个变量的某个设定关联的数据点 并以高亮显示
And so there's all sorts of interactive details that you can make available
所以你可以给用户展示各种可互动
to a user.
的细节
You just want to make them available only when they're requested and
你只是它们被需求时才展示出来
not all at once, so as to not overwhelm the viewer.
而不是一下全部展示 这样才不会让观察者感觉过度
So those are the basic steps for setting up a good
所以以上就是创建一个好的
information visualization system to understand abstract information.
用来了解抽象信息的信息可视化系统的基本步骤
That first step, you want to set up an overview to see all the data.
即第一步 你要建立能看到所有数据的概观
The second step is you want to be able to drill down to the details of
第二步是你可以通过集中 缩放 筛选
that data by focusing, zooming, filtering.
来研究数据的细节
And then that third step, you want to be able to provide details on your data, but
然后第三步 你可以按需提供
only when they're requested.
数据的细节
Only details on demand.
只提供所需求的细节
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community